Finding Aid for James J. Blanchard Papers, 1982-2002
Bentley Historical Library
- Issues Development, 1982-1990
  - Special Projects, 1983-1990
    - Citizens Protection Advisor (Candy Avery), 1986-1990
      - Fugitive Investigative Strike Team, 1989 (Box 126)
      - Furloughs, 1988 (Box 126)
      - Habitual Offender Statistics, 1989 (Box 126)
      - Halfway Houses, 1989-1990 (Box 126)
      - Immigration, 1987 (Box 127)
      - Inkster, 1990; 2 folders (Box 127)
      - Jail Overcrowding, 1988-1990 (Box 127)
      - Juvenile Justice, 1987-1990; 2 folders (Box 127)
      - Kalamazoo Criminal Justice Task Force, 1990 (Box 127)
      - Kent Co. Emergency Needs, 1990 (Box 127)
      - Mandatory Life Without Parole, 1988-1990 (Box 127)
      - Marijuana Eradication Program, 1988-1989 (Box 127)
      - Medical Malpractice, 1986-1987 (Box 127)
      - Michigan Law Enforcement Youth Advisory Council, 1988 (Box 127)
      - Michigan Model for Comprehensive Health Education, 1987-1990; 2 folders (Box 127)
      - Michigan Justice Training Fund, 1987-1990; 2 folders (Box 127)
      - MSU Symposium on Policing/Drugs, 1990 (Box 127)
      - Oakland County, 1987-1988 (Box 127)
      - Office of Criminal Justice, 1987-1990; 2 folders (Box 127)
      - Oil Spills, 1988-1990; 2 folders (Box 127)
      - Parole, 1990 (Box 128)
      - Partners Against Crime, 1989-1990; 4 folders (Box 128)
      - Prison Industries, 1990 (Box 128)
      - Prison Populations, 1989-1990; 2 folders (Box 128)
      - Prosecuting Attorneys' Association of Michigan, 1989-1990; 2 folders (Box 128)
      - Runaway and Youth Services, 1987 (Box 128)
      - Search and Seizure, 1988 (Box 128)
      - Sentencing, 1988-1990; 2 folders (Box 128)
      - Spreen, Johannes, 1989-1990 (Box 128)
      - State Appellate Defenders Office, 1989 (Box 128)
      - State/Local Partnership (Prisons), 1988-1990; 2 folders (Box 128)
      - State of the State, 1987-1989; 5 folders (Box 128)
        (See also Chief of Staff/ Executive Assistants, Boxes 20 and 26; Press Office Boxes 177-181, 187, 204-213)
      - State of the State, 1990; 2 folders (Box 129)
      - Student Assistance Programs, 1989 (Box 129)
      - Substance Abuse, 1989-1990; 4 folders (Box 129)
      - Uniform Crime Report, 1985-1987 (Box 129)
      - Urban Strategy Group, 1987 (Box 129)
      - Water Contamination, 1986 (Box 129)
      - Wayne County, 1989 (Box 129)
      - Wiretap, 1989-1990 (Box 129)
    - Public Investment Task Force (Robert Mitchell), 1983-1987
      - Committees, 1983-1987
        - Education, 1984-1986; 2 folders (Box 129)
        - Environment, 1983-1987; 10 folders (Box 129)
        - Government/Local Government, 1983-1986; 2 folders (Box 130)
        - Infrastructure, 1984-1987; 4 folders (Box 130)
        - Transportation, 1984-1987; 7 folders (Box 130)
      - Correspondence, 1983-1987; 10 folders (Box 130)
      - Meetings, 1983-1987; 15 folders (Box 131)
      - Public Hearings, 1987
        - General/Geographic, 1987; 3 folders (Box 131)
        - General/Geographic, 1987; 5 folders (Box 132)
        - Preliminary Reports, 1987 (Box 132)
        - Testimony/Subjects, 1987; 5 folders (Box 132)
      - Reports, 1984-1987
        - From Crisis to Opportunity, 1985 (Box 133)
        - Governor's Program to Rebuild Michigan, 1984-1987; 3 volumes (Box 133)
        - Michigan's Infrastructure, 1986 (Box 133)
        - Miscellaneous, 1985-1986 (Box 133)
        - Public Investment Data Summaries, 1984-1986; 6 folders (Box 133)
      - Topical, 1983-1987
        - Centennial Business Portraits, 1987 (Box 133)
        - Cheboygan, 1986 (Box 133)
        - Corrections, 1984-1987 (Box 133)
        - Michigan Association of Regions, 1984-1985 (Box 133)
        - Michigan Beyond 2000, circa 1986 (Box 133)
        - Michigan State Housing Development Authority, 1983 (Box 133)
        - Path to Prosperity, 1984 (Box 133)
        - Public Sector Consultants (Michigan In Brief), 1987-1988; 2 folders (Box 133)
        - Speeches, 1984-1986; 4 folders (with audiotapes) (Box 133)
        - State Building Authority, 1985 (Box 133)
        - Weatherization Alternatives, 1985 (Box 133)
- Legal (Mike Hodge), 1983-1990
  The Legal Division, 1983-1990 series consists of the papers of Mike Hodge, Blanchard's legal counsel. This series consists of ten linear feet of correspondence, briefs, memoranda, and reports related to a wide range of legal matters facing the governor. As Hodge became legal counsel during Blanchard's second term, the materials provide better coverage of the years 1987 to 1990. The researcher should note that the State Archives holds all materials related to pardons and extraditions. This series is broken down into three subseries: correspondence, departments, and topical.
  The departments and topical subseries should be viewed as complementary units as they were part of a single alphabet in Hodge's files. They were broken into two subseries in the course of processing in order to parallel other filing systems in the upper echelons of Blanchard's executive office. This should ease access, when this series is opened to research.
  - Correspondence, 1987-1990
    The correspondence subseries is arranged alphabetically by correspondent, usually a member of the legal or executive office staff, and comprises six linear inches. While physically thin, these materials are quite rich in substance given the positions of the principals and the nature of their discourse.
    - Avery, Candy, 1987-1990; 4 folders (Box 134)
    - Baldini, Tom, 1989-1990 (Box 134)
    - Blanchard, 1987-1990; 2 folders (Box 134)
    - Dean, Cam, 1987 (Box 134)
    - Griffiths, Martha, 1990 (Box 134)
    - Kandler, Bill, 1988-1990 (Box 134)
    - Linteau, Carol, 1990 (Box 134)
    - Morris, Greg, 1988-1990 (Box 134)
    - Nettles-Nickerson, Beverly, 1988 (Box 134)
    - Thayer, Ron, 1988-1990 (Box 134)
    - Weiss, Steve, 1988-1990 (Box 134)
  - Departments, 1984-1990
    The department subseries consists of four linear feet of materials arranged alphabetically by department. As one might expect given the legal thrust of this office, the thickest and richest materials are found in the departmental files of the attorney general, corrections, and state police. Surprisingly, the files provide substantive documentation on the citizens' review committee on civil service and the departments of management and budget and public health.
    - Aging, Office of Services to, 1988-1990 (Box 134)
    - Agriculture, 1986-1990 (Box 134)
    - Attorney General, 1987-1990
      - General/Office, 1987-1990; 5 folders (Box 134)
      - Kelley, Frank, 1987-1990; 2 folders (Box 134)
    - Civil Service, 1987-1990
      - General, 1988-1990; 3 folders (Box 135)
      - Citizens' Review Committee, 1987-1988; 2 folders (Box 135)
      - Contractual Services, 1989 (Box 135)
    - Commerce, 1988-1990; 3 folders (Box 135)
    - Corrections, 1984-1990
      - General, 1987-1990; 6 folders (Box 135)
      - Community Corrections, 1988-1990; 2 folders (Box 135)
      - Consent Decree (USA v. Michigan), 1985-1990; 3 folders (Box 135)
      - Corrections Officers Safety, 1984-1990
        - General (includes riot plans), 1985-1987 (Box 136)
        - Attorney General's Report, 1987 (Box 136)
        - Budd Homicide, 1987; 2 folders (Box 136)
        - Hostage Incidents (Huron Valley Men), 1990 (Box 136)
      - Ferris B.A. Program, 1988-1989 (Box 136)
      - Prisons Construction, 1984-1989
        - Carson City, 1984-1986 (Box 136)
        - Detroit, 1985-1987; 2 folders (Box 136)
        - Farms, 1985-1986 (Box 136)
        - Financing, 1985-1987 (Box 136)
        - Overcrowding, 1984-1989; 3 folders (Box 136)
      - Public Sector Consultants Report, 1989 (Box 136)
      - Sentencing, 1986-1989 (Box 136)
      - State and Local Partnership, 1990 (Box 136)
      - Transfer of Prisoners (Canada), 1988-1990 (Box 136)
    - Education, 1989-1990 (Box 136)
    - Labor, 1987-1990; 4 folders (Box 137)
    - Licensing and Regulation, 1988-1990; 2 folders (Box 137)
    - Management and Budget, 1988-1990; 3 folders (Box 137)
    - Military Affairs, 1988-1990; 2 folders (Box 137)
    - Mental Health, 1987-1988 (Box 137)
    - Natural Resources, 1988-1990; 2 folders (Box 137)
    - Public Health, 1988-1990; 4 folders (Box 137)
    - Secretary of State, 1988 (Box 137)
    - Social Services, 1987-1990 (Box 137)
    - State Employer, Office of, 1987-1990; 2 folders (Box 138)
    - State Police, 1986-1990
      - General, 1987-1990; 3 folders (Box 138)
      - Detroit Freeway, 1989 (Box 138)
      - Financial Reports, 1986-1989 (Box 138)
      - Helicopter, 1990 (Box 138)
      - Speed Limits (65 MPH), 1987-1988 (Box 138)
    - Transportation, 1988-1990 (Box 138)
    - Treasury, 1988-1990 (Box 138)
  - Topical, 1983-1990
    The topical subseries runs just over five linear feet and is arranged alphabetically. The strong areas of this topical file are those related to crime and corrections, ongoing legal cases, potential legal impact of legislation, and the state supreme court. Again, there are unexpected strengths within these topical files, materials on campaign financing and a complete list of Blanchard's executive orders being just two instances of this documentation
    - Abortion, 1988-1990; 2 folders (Box 138)
    - Action Report, 1988 (Box 138)
    - Appropriations, 1987-1989 (Box 138)
    - Automated Fingerprinting (AFIS), 1987 (Box 138)
    - A, 1989-1990 (Box 138)
    - Blue Cross/Blue Shield, 1984-1989 (Box 138)
    - Bond Issues (Proposals C and D), 1988 (Box 138)
    - B, 1987-1990 (Box 138)
    - Campaign Financing, 1988-1989; 2 folders (Box 138)
    - Carrolltown Township Recall, 1990 (Box 138)
    - Consumers' Power, 1988-1990
      - General, 1988-1990; 3 folders (Box 139)
      - Cogeneration, 1988-1990; 2 folders (Box 139)
    - Cooney et al v. Michigan, 1990 (Box 139)
    - Corktown, 1988-1990 (Box 139)
    - Council on Environment, 1990 (Box 139)
    - Crime, 1984-1990
      - General, 1984-1990; 4 folders (Box 139)
      - Juvenile Justice, 1985-1988; 2 folders (Box 139)
    - C, 1987-1990 (Box 139)
    - Detroit, 1988-1990; 2 folders (Box 139)
    - Drug Initiatives (Michigan), 1988-1989 (Box 139)
    - Dutko, Dennis, 1989 (Box 139)
    - D, 1989-1990 (Box 139)
    - Electronic Fund Transfer, 1988 (Box 140)
    - Energy Emergency, 1990 (Box 140)
    - Executive Directives, 1983-1990 (Box 140)
    - Executive Orders, 1983-1990; 8 folders (Box 140)
    - Extraditions, 1988-1990 (Box 140)
    - E, 1988-1989 (Box 140)
    - Fisher (Burtha) House, 1989 (Box 140)
    - Freedom of Information Act Requests, 1983-1990; 4 folders (Box 140)
    - Friedland Iron & Metal Co., 1988 (Box 140)
    - F, 1988-1990 (Box 140)
    - Governor's Fire Safety Task Force, 1989-1990 (Box 140)
    - G, 1988-1990 (Box 140)
    - Hazardous Materials, 1989 (Box 140)
    - H, 1987-1989 (Box 140)
    - Indian Gambling (Escanaba), 1989 (Box 140)
    - Inheritance Tax, 1989-1990 (Box 140)
    - Insurance (Automobiles), 1988-1990 (Box 140)
    - IRS Audit, 1987-1989 (Box 140)
    - I, 1988-1990 (Box 140)
    - Jackson County Prosecutor, 1987 (Box 140)
    - Joint Operating Agreement, 1988-1989 (Box 140)
    - Jones and Laughlin Steel, 1987 (Box 140)
    - J, 1988-1990 (Box 140)
    - K, 1988-1990 (Box 140)
    - L, 1988-1990 (Box 141)
    - Mackinac Bridge Accident, 1989 (Box 141)
    - Mackinac Island Fire, 1988 (Box 141)
    - Mayors' Meeting, 1990 (Box 141)
    - McCallum v. Michigan, 1987-1989 (Box 141)
    - Medical Malpractice, 1989-1990 (Box 141)
    - Michigan Bell, 1988-1990 (Box 141)
    - Michigan Democratic Party, 1989-1990 (Box 141)
    - Michigan Equal Employment Business Opportunity Council, 1989-1990 (Box 141)
    - Michigan Higher Education Assistance, 1988 (Box 141)
    - Michigan Pride Committee, 1988-1990 (Box 141)
    - Michigan Seal of Quality, 1989 (Box 141)
    - Michigan Sheriffs' Association, 1989 (Box 141)
    - Michigan Soft Drink Association, 1990 (Box 141)
    - Michigan Technological University, 1989 (Box 141)
    - Midland Drain Commission, 1988-1989 (Box 141)
    - Miller, Canfield, Paddock, & Stone, 1989-1990 (Box 141)
    - Mini-RICO, 1988-1989 (Box 141)
    - Multi-County Grand Juries, 1989 (Box 141)
    - M, 1988-1990 (Box 141)
    - National Guard, 1988-1990 (Box 141)
    - 911 Conference, 1988 (Box 141)
    - Nu-Vision, 1988 (Box 141)
    - N, 1988-1989 (Box 141)
    - O, 1988-1989 (Box 141)
    - Parental Consent for Medical Treatment, 1990 (Box 141)
    - Partners Against Crime, 1989-1990; 3 folders (Box 141)
    - Perry Drugs, 1990 (Box 141)
    - Product Liability, 1986-1989; 4 folders (Box 142)
    - Proposal A, 1989-1990; 2 folders (Box 142)
    - Prosecuting Attorneys' Association of Michigan, 1987-1990; 2 folders (Box 142)
    - Prosecuting Attorneys Forfeiture, 1990 (Box 142)
    - Prosecutors' Reimbursement, 1987 (Box 142)
    - Public Service Commission, 1987-1990; 3 folders (Box 142)
    - P, 1988-1990 (Box 142)
    - Q, 1985-1990 (Box 142)
    - R, 1988-1990 (Box 142)
    - Savings and Loan in Michigan, 1989 (Box 142)
    - Senate Bill 119 (Liquor Control), 1989 (Box 142)
    - Shelby Township, 1988-1989 (Box 142)
    - State Administrative, 1987-1989 (Box 142)
    - State Appellate Defender, 1987-1990 (Box 142)
    - State Bar of Michigan, 1987 (Box 142)
    - Supreme Court of Michigan, 1983-1990; 3 folders (Box 142)
    - S, 1988-1990 (Box 142)
    - Toxic Substance Control, 1990 (Box 143)
    - T, 1988-1990 (Box 143)
    - United Auto Workers, 1987-1990 (Box 143)
    - United States District Court, 1988-1989 (Box 143)
    - United States Olympic Committee, 1988 (Box 143)
    - United Technologies Automotive, 1989 (Box 143)
    - Utilities, 1984-1988 (Box 143)
    - U-V, 1988-1990 (Box 143)
    - Wayne County, 1986-1990
      - General, 1986-1989; 3 folders (Box 143)
      - Indigent Medical Care, 1987 (Box 143)
      - Jail Privatization, 1988 (Box 143)
      - Resident Hospital, 1987-1990 (Box 143)
      - Westland Medical Center, 1987 (Box 143)
      - Miscellaneous/Notes, 1985-1987 (Box 143)
    - Wiretapping, 1990 (Box 143)
    - Wisconsin Diversion, 1990 (Box 143)
    - W, 1988-1990 (Box 143)
    - Z, 1988-1990 (Box 143)
  - Miscellaneous (later accession)
    - State Accident Fund
      - Employment Agreements, 1986 (Box 143)
      - General, 1985-1986 (Box 143)
      - General, 1988 (Box 143)
      - Various topics, 1989 (Box 143)
      - Various topics, 1990 (Box 143)
      - Notes (Box 143)
      - Court of Appeals, 1988 (Box 143)
    - Low-level Radioactive Waste Authority (exchanges with Attorney General; correspondence (Box 143)
  - Departments / Topical, 1983-1990; 1987-1990
    - Abortion (Box 347)
    - Action Report (Box 347)
    - Administrative Rules
      - General, 1987-1990 (Box 347)
      - Commerce, 1988; 2 folders (Box 347)
      - Education, Department of, 1987 (Box 347)
      - Labor, 1988 (Box 347)
      - Licensing & Regulations, 1988 (Box 347)
      - Natural Resources, Department of, 1988; 2 folders (Box 347)
      - State Police, 1988 (Box 347)
      - Worker's Compensation Health Care Services, 1988 (Box 347)
    - Affirmative Action (Box 347)
    - AFIS (Box 347)
    - AFL/CIO (Box 347)
    - Agriculture, Dept. of
      - Bonds, 1987 (Box 347)
      - Food Division (Box 347)
      - Sand Livestock (Box 347)
    - Aids (Box 347)
    - Anti-Drug Initiatives (Box 347)
    - Assault Weapons (Box 347)
    - Attorney General
      - General, 1987 (Box 347)
      - Agriculture, Dept. of (Box 347)
      - Correspondence
        - 1988 (Box 347)
        - 1989 (Box 347)
        - 1990 (Box 347)
      - Riley, Dorothy Comstock (Box 347)
      - Safety of Michigan's Correctional Officers, 1987 (Box 347)
    - Avery, Candy, Correspondence, 3 folders (Box 348)
    - B (Box 348)
    - Ballot Tax Proposals (Box 348)
    - Bills, House & Senate, 5 folders (Box 348)
    - Blanchard Endorsements (Box 348)
    - Bylaws-Various Committees (Box 348)
    - C (Box 348)
    - Campaign Finance Act, Enrolled Senate Bill No. 448 (Box 348)
    - Canadian Consulate General (Box 348)
    - Civil Rights (Box 348)
    - Civil Service, Dept. of
      - General (Box 348)
      - Citizens Review Committee, 2 folders (Box 348)
      - Conflict of Interest, 1989 (Box 348)
    - Commerce, Dept. of
      - General (Box 348)
      - Bonds (JDA) (Box 348)
      - Meyer, Larry L. (Box 348)
    - Consumer's Power
      - General (Box 348)
      - Cogeneration, 1988-1989; 2 folders (Box 348)
      - Electricity Growth & the Michigan Economy (Box 348)
    - Corrections, Dept. of
      - General, 4 folders (Box 348)
      - Baraga County (Box 348)
      - Boot Camps, Detroit (Box 348)
      - Campbell, William, aka Alan Rogers, Jr. (Box 348)
      - Clearinghouse for Substances Act, CSA (Box 349)
      - Clippings & Articles, 3 folders (Box 349)
      - Community Corrections Legislation (Box 349)
      - Correspondence, 2 folders (Box 349)
      - Cottec, Michael (Box 349)
      - Death Penalty (Box 349)
      - Federal Grand Jury Request (Box 349)
      - Halfway House (Box 349)
      - Incident Reports (Box 349)
      - Jail Financing (Box 349)
      - Macomb County Prison (Box 349)
      - Material and Information (Box 349)
      - Overcrowding, 2 folders (Box 349)
      - Personal Property Claims of Inmates (Box 349)
      - Policies & Procedures (Box 349)
      - Prisoner Transfer Treaty (Box 349)
      - Prisons
        - Articles (Box 349)
        - Assault on Correction Officers (Box 349)
        - Early Releases (Box 349)
        - Guards (Box 349)
        - Industries (Box 349)
        - Investigation, Welborn (Box 349)
        - Life Sentencing (Box 349)
        - Overcrowding, Construction (Box 349)
        - Plymouth Center for Human Development (Box 349)
        - Pole Building Facilities (Box 349)
        - Population Projections (Box 349)
        - Riot Control (Box 349)
        - Riots (Box 349)
        - Site Possibilities (Box 349)
      - Proposed Affiliation Agreement (Box 349)
      - Recollet, Kenneth (Box 349)
      - Reform Negotiations (Box 349)
      - Reimbursement (Box 349)
      - Sentencing Guidelines (Box 349)
      - Sentencing Reform (Box 349)
      - Stats
        - General, 2 folders (Box 350)
        - 1988 (Box 350)
        - Foreign Born Residents (Box 350)
        - New York, 1990 (Box 350)
      - Supervision Programs, Intensive/Maximum (Box 350)
      - Thumb Regional Correctional Facility (Box 350)
      - Transfers
        - General (Box 350)
        - McCreary, 1989 (Box 350)
      - USA v Michigan Consent Decree (Box 350)
      - Work & Learn Camps (Box 350)
    - Correspondence
      - Detroit (Box 350)
      - Finance Office (Box 350)
      - Governor's Signature, prepared for (Box 350)
      - Nettles-Nickerson, Beverley, Memorandums, 1988 (Box 350)
    - Crime
      - General (Box 350)
      - Booklets, Information (Box 350)
      - Cabinet Council (Box 350)
      - Crime Legislation (Box 350)
      - Drugs (Box 350)
      - Handguns (Box 350)
      - Heinous Crimes (Box 350)
      - Package, 2 folders (Box 350)
      - Survey (Box 350)
    - Criminal Justice, office of
      - General, 2 folders (Box 350)
      - Causes, Consequences, and Options (Box 350)
      - Correspondence (Box 350)
      - Crime Facts, 1987 (Box 350)
      - Crime Facts, National & Regional (Box 350)
      - Crime Index, 2 folders (Box 350)
    - DNA Profiling (Box 350)
    - DARE (Box 350)
    - Detroit Edison (Box 350)
    - Disasters (Box 350)
    - Elections
      - General (Box 350)
      - Certificates (Box 351)
      - General, 1986 (Box 351)
      - General, 1988; 3 folders (Box 351)
      - General unofficial, 1990 (Box 351)
      - Party Primaries (Box 351)
      - Primary, 1990; 3 folders (Box 351)
    - Electoral College, 2 folders (Box 351)
    - Emergency Rules, 1988; 2 folders (Box 351)
    - Energy (Box 351)
    - Executive Agreements (Box 351)
    - Executive Directives, 1983-1990; 6 folders (Box 351)
    - Executive Office
      - General (Box 351)
      - Correspondence (Box 351)
      - Clyne, Arthur Jay (Box 351)
      - Governor, Office of the (Box 351)
      - Great Lakes, Office of the (Box 351)
      - Move, the (Box 351)
      - Office Equipment (Box 351)
      - Scheduling (Box 351)
      - Special Messages (Box 351)
      - Speech Materials (Box 351)
      - Superconducting Super Collider (Box 351)
    - Executive Orders, 1988-1989; 4 folders (Box 351)
    - F (Box 351)
    - Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) (Box 351)
    - Fetter, Steven M., 1988 (Box 351)
    - Food Dealers and Dual Regulation (Box 351)
    - Franchise Act (Box 351)
    - Freedom of Information Act (Box 351)
    - Fugitive Investigative Strike Team (FIST) (Box 351)
    - G (Box 351)
    - General Motors (Box 351)
    - Governor
      - Conference on Juvenile Justice (Box 351)
      - Health Care Cost Management Team (Box 351)
      - Lieutenant, Presiding Officer (Box 351)
      - Residence (Box 352)
      - Task Force
        - Employment Opportunities for Older Citizens (Box 352)
        - Insurance (Box 352)
    - Gun Control (Box 352)
    - Higher Education Bankruptcy Task Force (Box 352)
    - Hospital Reimbursement Lawsuit (Box 352)
    - Indian Fishing Treaty and Lawsuit Negotiations (Box 352)
    - Indian Gambling (Box 352)
    - Inspector General, Creation of (Box 352)
    - Insurance
      - General (Box 352)
      - Accident Fund, Workers Compensation (Box 352)
      - Auto (Box 352)
      - Auto Roll Back Legislation (Box 352)
      - Bureau, 1988-1989; 2 folders (Box 352)
      - Cadillac Insurance Company (Box 352)
      - Clippings and Articles (Box 352)
    - Internal Revenue Service (IRS)
      - General (Box 352)
      - Income Tax (Box 352)
    - J & L Steel (Box 352)
    - Juvenile Delinquents
      - General (Box 352)
      - Camps, 1987 (Box 352)
    - L (Box 352)
    - Labor, Department of (Box 352)
    - Licensing & Regulation, Department of
      - General (Box 352)
      - Credit Insurance (Box 352)
      - Triplicate Prescriptions (Box 352)
    - M (Box 352)
    - Mackinac Center (Box 352)
    - Macomb County List, Personnel (Box 352)
    - Management & Budget, Dept. of
      - General (Box 352)
      - Correspondence (Box 352)
      - Emergency Telephone Service Commission (Box 352)
      - Fiscal Year Budget, 1990-1991 (Box 352)
    - Maplehurst, 1987 (Box 352)
    - Marital Privilege Bill (Box 352)
    - Market Opinion Research, MI Tax Issues, 1989 (Box 352)
    - MCADY Red Ribbon Campaign (Box 352)
    - Medicaid Abortions (Box 352)
    - Medical Malpractice, Nick Smith (Box 352)
    - MEEBOC (Box 352)
    - Memos to File (Box 352)
    - Mental Health (Box 352)
    - Michigan
      - Association of Counties (Box 352)
      - Corrections Organization (Box 352)
      - District Judges' Association, Annual Conference, 1988 (Box 352)
      - Food Dealers Association (Box 352)
      - Ontario, Law Revision Commission (Box 352)
      - State Council of OCI's (Box 353)
      - Trial Lawyers Association (Box 353)
    - Midland Drain Commissioner (Box 353)
    - Midland Plant (Box 353)
    - Miller, Diane (Box 353)
    - Minority Counsel Demonstration Program (Box 353)
    - Minority & Women Procurement (Box 353)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Clippings (Box 353)
      - Correspondence (Box 353)
    - M-PACE (Box 353)
    - MSPTA Contract (Box 353)
    - National Governor's Association (NGA)
      - General (Box 353)
      - Correspondence (Box 353)
      - Legal Center (Box 353)
    - National Guard, Abandoned Houses (Box 353)
    - National Institute of Justice (Box 353)
    - Natural Resources, Dept. of
      - General, 2 folders (Box 353)
      - Council of Great Lakes Governors (Box 353)
    - Nuclear Power Plants (Box 353)
    - Nuclear Waste (Box 353)
    - Old Plaza Renovation (Box 353)